<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Francisco Mendonca&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Francisco Mendonca&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.134.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 11:56:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick Docker Networking Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dockernetworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 11:56:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dockernetworking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;``s
This tutorial focuses on two of the several networks Docker has at our disposal, Bridge and Overlay. These two networks allow for the similar uses under different cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Docker, a Bridge Network is the default network. If no network is specified, Docker will assume that, when a container is deployed, it will use the default bridge network. The goal of the bridge network is to allow containers to communicate while remaining isolated from the hosts (the machine where the container are running) networks - and the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Drafts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/publishingdrafts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 13:13:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/publishingdrafts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Normally, there is no reason to publish drafts. I mean, who wants to display to the world their unfinished, unpolished and unverfied work? Aparently me. The idea was borned after I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-public&#34;&gt;Learning in Public&lt;/a&gt; by Shawn Wang. The premise is simple: while the majority of us learn in private, learning by publicaly displaying what you know about a subject, and submitting yourself to the wider public critisism has the ability of actually improving how &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; you learn. Because there&amp;rsquo;s always someone out there who knows more than you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decorators in Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pythondecorators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 21:21:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pythondecorators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python is renowned for its exceptional versatility, making it ideal for diverse applications, from web development to data science. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into a powerful feature known as Decorators. Although I had not explored Decorators for quite some time, I decided it was finally time to thoroughly understand and master them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-nested-functions-in-python&#34;&gt;Understanding Nested Functions in Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into decorators, it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to understand nested functions in Python. A nested function is defined within another function, and it can access variables from the enclosing scope. Here’s an example to illustrate this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 11:54:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After one year in my PhD, I accumulated a lot of notes, both hand-written or written using tools like Obsidian, Notion, or similar. I&amp;rsquo;ve loss track of most notes I took, and do not actively keep track of most. I thought a blog was exactly what I needed, somewhere to discuss more in depth some of the work I&amp;rsquo;m developing, and other projects I come across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this blog comes to serve some use to at least me - a place where I can develop further certain ideas, skills, and other tid bits I might find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
